A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Education and Public Policy Program (EPP), Office of the Arts, Program Files FA640
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Program Files, 1955-1977; XIII
  - Visual Artists, Program for -- Nominating Form, 1958 (Box 47)
  - Visual Artists, Program for -- List of Grant Winners, 1958 (Box 47)
    Grantees include: Grantees include: Josef Albers, Elmer Bishoff, Hyman Bloom, Edwin Dickinson, Philip Guston, Raoul Hague, Conrad Marca-Relli, Reuben Nakian, Theodore Roszak, Adja Yunkers.
  - Visual Artists, Program for -- List of American Federation of Arts retrospective winners, 1958 (Box 47)
    See also Ford Foundation Project file C-620: Grants in Aid program for visual artists; and Grant files: 05800385 (PA58-385), American Federation of Arts, STIMULATION OF PUBLIC INTEREST IN WORKS OF MATURE ARTISTS; 05900120 (PA59-120), Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), PROGRAM FOR VISUAL ARTISTS; 06000084 (PA60-84), Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), PROGRAM FOR VISUAL ARTISTS; and 06090071 (PA60-71), Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), PURCHASE PRIZES AWARDED IN CONNECTION WITH 1959 PROGRAM FOR VISUAL ARTISTS.
    1959 Grantees include: Milton Avery, Andrew Dasburg, Jose de Creeft, Lee Gatch, Mauricio Lasansky, Carl Morris, William Pachner, Walter Quirt, Abraham Rattner, Hugo Schrag, Everett Spruce.
    1960 Grantees include: Cameron Booth, Paul Burlin, Jose de Rivera, Balcomb Greene, Misch Kohn, Jacob Lawrence, and Karl Zerbe.
  - Visual Artists, Program for -- List of Nominators, 1958 (Box 47)
  - Visual Artists, Program for -- Financial Schedule, 1958 (Box 47)
  - Visual Artists, Program for -- Confidential Inquiry Form, 1958 (Box 47)
  - Visual Artists, Program for -- List of Nominees (by region), 1958 (Box 47)
  - Visual Artists, Program for -- List of Finalists, 1958 (Box 47)
  - Visual Artists, Program for -- List of Nominees, 1958 (Box 47)
  - Visual Artists, Program for -- Instructions to Collection Center -- Region 1, 1958 (Box 47)
  - Visual Artists, Program for -- Instructions to Collection Center -- Region 2, 1958 (Box 47)
  - Visual Artists, Program for -- Instructions to Collection Center -- Region 3, 1958 (Box 47)
  - Visual Artists, Program for -- Instructions to Collection Center -- Region 4, 1958 (Box 47)
  - Visual Artists, Program for -- Instructions to Collection Center -- Region 5, 1958 (Box 47)
  - Visual Artists, Program for -- Instructions to Collection Center -- Region 6, 1958 (Box 47)
  - Visual Artists, Program for -- Instructions to Collection Center -- Region 7, 1958 (Box 47)
  - Visual Artists, Program for -- Instructions to Collection Center -- Region 8, 1958 (Box 47)
  - Visual Artists, Program for -- Instructions to Collection Center -- Region 9, 1958 (Box 47)
  - Visual Artists, Program for -- Instructions to Collection Center -- Region 10, 1958 (Box 47)
  - Visual Artists, Program for -- Instructions to Collection Center -- Region 11, 1958 (Box 47)
  - Visual Artists, Program for -- Instructions to Collection Center -- Region 12, 1958 (Box 47)
  - Visual Artists, Program for -- Instructions to Artists -- Regions 1-6, 1958 (Box 47)
  - Visual Artists, Program for -- Instructions to Artists -- Regions 7-12, 1958 (Box 47)
  - Visual Artists, Program for -- Identification Tag, 1958 (Box 47)
  - Visual Artists, Program for -- List of Unsuccessful Nominees, 1958 (Box 47)
  - Directors, Program for -- Background, 1958 (Box 48)
  - Directors, Program for -- Correspondence, 1958 (Box 48)
  - Directors, Program for -- Forms, 1958 (Box 48)
  - Directors, Program for -- Grant Actions, 1958 (Box 48)
  - Directors, Program for -- Judges' Correspondence, 1958 (Box 48)
  - Directors, Program for -- Judges' Meeting, 1958 (Box 48)
  - Directors, Program for -- Nominator's Correspondence, 1958 (Box 48)
  - Directors, Program for -- Nominees' Correspondence, 1958 (Box 48)
  - Directors, Program for -- Press Releases and Fact Sheet, 1958 (Box 48)
  - Directors, Program for -- Grantees -- Alley Theatre/Vance, Nina, 1958 (Box 48)
  - Directors, Program for -- Grantees -- Ball, William, 1958 (Box 48)
  - Directors, Program for -- Grantees -- Ben Avram, Rachmael, 1958 (Box 48)
  - Directors, Program for -- Grantees -- Bowmer, Angus L., 1958-1966 (Box 48)
  - Directors, Program for -- Grantees -- Bowmer, Angus L., 1958 (Box 48)
  - Directors, Program for -- Grantees -- Blau, Herbert, 1958 (Box 48)
  - Directors, Program for -- Grantees -- Clancy, James H., 1958 (Box 48)
  - Directors, Program for -- Grantees -- Fichandler, Zelda, 1958 (Box 48)
  - Directors, Program for -- Grantees -- Reich, John, 1958 (Box 48)
  - Directors, Program for -- Grantees -- Schneider, Alan, 1958 (Box 48)
  - Directors, Program for -- Grantees -- Scism, Mack, 1958 (Box 48)
  - Directors, Program for -- Background, 1959 (Box 48)
  - Directors, Program for -- Correspondence, 1959 (Box 48)
  - Directors, Program for -- Forms, 1959 (Box 48)
  - Directors, Program for -- Grant Actions, 1959 (Box 48)
  - Directors, Program for -- Judges' Correspondence, 1959 (Box 48)
  - Directors, Program for -- Judges' Meeting, 1959 (Box 48)
  - Directors, Program for -- Nominators' Correspondence, 1959 (Box 48)
  - Directors, Program for -- Nominees' Correspondence (Box 48)
  - Directors, Program for -- Press Releases and Fact Sheet, 1959 (Box 48)
  - Directors, Program for -- Grantees -- Baker, Word, 1959 (Box 48)
  - Directors, Program for -- Grantees -- Epstein, Alvin, 1959 (Box 48)
  - Directors, Program for -- Grantees -- Fletcher, Alvin, 1959 (Box 48)
  - Directors, Program for -- Grantees -- Frankel, Gene, 1959 (Box 48)
  - Directors, Program for -- Grantees -- Lawrence, Philip, 1959 (Box 48)
  - Directors, Program for -- Grantees -- Rill, Eli, 1959 (Box 48)
  - Directors, Program for -- Grantees -- Vaughan, Stuart, 1959 (Box 48)
  - Curatorial Training Program -- Forms, 1965-1977 (Box 49)
    See also: Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), 06490130 (PA64-130): PROGRAM FOR THE TRAINING OF MUSEUM CURATORIAL PERSONNEL (Reel 2059;2170;2171;2173;2292;2293;2294).
  - Curatorial Training Program -- Background, 1962-1966 (Box 49)
  - Curatorial Training Program -- Grant Actions, 1963-1974 (Box 49)
  - Curatorial Training Program -- Judges Correspondence, 1966-1972 (Box 49)
  - Curatorial Training Program -- Judges Meeting, 1964 (Box 49)
  - Curatorial Training Program -- Judges Meeting, 1965 (Box 49)
  - Curatorial Training Program -- Judges Meeting, 1966 (Box 49)
  - Curatorial Training Program -- Judges Meeting, 1967 (Box 49)
  - Curatorial Training Program -- Judges Meeting, Nominees Material, 1967 March 3-4 (Reel 9334)
  - Curatorial Training Program -- Judges Meeting, 1968 (Box 49)
  - Curatorial Training Program -- Judges Meeting, Nominees Material, 1968 April 1-2 (Reel 9335)
  - Curatorial Training Program -- Judges Meeting, 1969 (Box 49)
  - Curatorial Training Program -- Judges Meeting, Nominees Material, 1969 March 30-21 (Reel 9336)
  - Curatorial Training Program -- Judges Meeting, 1970 (Box 49)
  - Curatorial Training Program -- Judges Meeting, 1971 (Box 49)
  - Curatorial Training Program -- Judges Meeting, Mar 13-14, 1972 (Box 49)
  - Curatorial Training Program -- Statistics, 1965-1972 (Box 49)
  - Curatorial Training Program -- Status Reports, 1966-1975 (Box 49)
  - Curatorial Training Program -- Press Releases, 1964-1971 (Box 49)
  - Curatorial Training Program -- Timetables, 1965-1972 (Box 49)
  - Discretionary Grants -- Background, 1962-1964 (Box 49)
  - Discretionary Grants -- Correspondence, 1963-1967 (Box 49)
  - Discretionary Grants -- Grant Actions, 1962-1970 (Box 49)
  - Economic and Financial Survey of Performing Groups -- Background/Planning, 1970-1971 (Box 49)
  - Economic and Financial Survey of Performing Groups -- Background/Planning, 1972-1973 (Box 49)
  - Economic and Financial Survey of Performing Groups -- Background/Planning (1/2), 1974-1975 (Box 49)
  - Economic and Financial Survey of Performing Groups -- Background/Planning (2/2), 1974-1975 (Box 49)
  - Economic and Financial Survey of Performing Groups -- Background/Marder Associates, Inc., 1971-1972 (Box 49)
  - Economic and Financial Survey of Performing Groups -- Conferences, 1971-1972 (Box 49)
  - Economic and Financial Survey of Performing Groups -- Forms, 1968-1975 (Box 49)
  - Economic and Financial Survey of Performing Groups -- Grant Actions, 1970-1975 (Box 49)
  - Economic and Financial Survey of Performing Groups -- Press Releases, 1971-1974 (Box 49)
  - Economic and Financial Survey of Performing Groups -- Consultants A-G, 1970-1976 (Box 49)
  - Economic and Financial Survey of Performing Groups -- Consultants H-Z, 1970-1975 (Box 49)
  - Purchase Program -- Evaluation, Mar 1965 (Box 50)
  - Purchase Program -- Background, 1961-1966 (Box 50)
  - Purchase Program -- Forms, 1961-1962 (Box 50)
  - Purchase Program -- Grant Actions, 1961-1962 (Box 50)
  - Purchase Program -- Judges Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 50)
  - Purchase Program -- Press Releases, 1961-1963 (Box 50)
  - Purchase Program -- Summaries, 1962-1964 (Box 50)
  - Purchase Program -- Correspondence A-Z (25 folders), 1961-1965 (Box 50)
  - Purchase Program -- Grantees A-Z (25 folders), 1961-1971 (Box 50)
  - Purchase Program -- Particular Museums -- Art Institute of Chicago, 1961-1965 (Box 50)
  - Purchase Program -- Particular Museums -- Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1961-1964 (Box 50)
  - Purchase Program -- Particular Museums -- (Houston) Museum of Fine Arts, 1961-1963 (Box 50)
  - Purchase Program -- Particular Museums -- Illinois, University of, 1961-1963 (Box 50)
  - Purchase Program -- Particular Museums -- Nelson Gallery of Art, 1961-1964 (Box 50)
  - Purchase Program -- Particular Museums -- Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts, 1961-1964 (Box 50)
  - Purchase Program -- Particular Museums -- Salt Lake Art Center, 1962-1964 (Box 50)
  - Purchase Program -- Particular Museums -- San Francisco Art Institute, 1962-1963 (Box 50)
  - Purchase Program -- Particular Museums -- Seattle Art Museum, 1961-1965 (Box 50)
  - Purchase Program -- Particular Museums -- Silvermine Guild of Artists, 1964-1965 (Box 50)
  - Purchase Program -- Particular Museums -- Walker Art Center, 1961-1965 (Box 50)
  - Purchase Program -- Particular Museums -- Whitney Museum of American Art, 1961-1965 (Box 50)
  - Reporters, Editors and Critics Program -- Background, 1961-1965 (Box 50)
    See also Ford Foundation Grant file 06400212 (PA64-212), Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), PROGRAM FOR REPORTERS, EDITORS AND CRITICS IN THE VISUAL AND PERFORMING ARTS.
  - Reporters, Editors and Critics Program -- Correspondence, 1963-1965 (Box 50)
  - Reporters, Editors and Critics Program -- Forms, 1963 (Box 50)
  - Reporters, Editors and Critics Program -- Grant Actions, 1964-1965 (Box 50)
  - Reporters, Editors and Critics Program -- Grantees First Year, 1961-1967 (Box 50)
    1963 Grantees include: Robert Brustein (book on improvisational theater); Maxine C. Gray (project to strengthen regional arts criticism); T.E. Kalem (attend theaters in England and Europe); Stanley Kauffman (visit film directors, producers, writers, and actors in Europe); Jules Langsner (travel project for a critic of art and architecture); Esther McCoy (survey of architects under the age of thirty-five in the United States); Eric Salzman (visit major new music centers in Europe); Franz Schulze, (travel and writing); Jerry Tallmer, (visit European theaters); Wolfe Von Eckardt (critical report on current urban design in major American cities, and comparisons to contemporary urban projects in Europe); and Peter B. Yates (travel the U.S. to discover and meet with creative meet creative artists).
    1964 Grantees include: Jean R. Allan (travel and study of American art); Renee R. Hall (visit professional and educational dance centers in the U.S.); Ann H. Holmes (observe resident and repertory theaters in the U.S.); Edward T. Kelly (study of contemporary art in the Soviet Union and Eastern Europe); Robert C. Marsh (study of contemporary American opera); Richard O. Martin (study of ballet); Mary Fuller McChesney (audio tape interviews with artists, and book); Julius Novick (study of theater); Gordon M. Rogoff (study of resident theater companies); Jean M. White (development of a program for the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts); and Clair Wolfe (study Dada concept and contemporary developments in Pop Art and New Realism).
  - Reporters, Editors and Critics Program -- Grantees Second Year, 1964-1969 (Box 50)
  - Purchase Program A-D, 1961-1964; Photos (Box 51)
  - Purchase Program E-L, 1961-1964; Photos (Box 51)
  - Purchase Program M-R, 1961-1964; Photos (Box 51)
  - Purchase Program S-Z, 1961-1964; Photos (Box 51)
  - Experiments, Demonstrations and Studies -- Background, 1962-1967 (Box 52)
  - Grants-in-Aid Programs -- Background, 1958-1970 (Box 52)
  - Grants-in-Aid Programs -- Appropriations for Administration, 1959-1966 (Box 52)
  - Grants-in-Aid Programs -- Appropriations for Awards, 1957-1973 (Box 52)
  - Grants-in-Aid Programs -- Statistics, 1967-1972 (Box 52)
  - Grants-in-Aid Programs -- Timetables, 1965-1972 (Box 52)
  - Grants-in-Aid Programs -- Grant Actions, 1974 (Box 52)
  - Humanistic Scholarship and Research -- Background, 1962-1968 (Box 52)
  - Humanistic Scholarship and Research -- Grant Actions and Appropriations, 1962-1970 (Box 52)
  - Humanistic Scholarship and Research -- Background, 1966-1972 (Box 52)
  - Humanistic Scholarship and Research -- Forms, 1967-1973 (Box 52)
  - Humanistic Scholarship and Research -- Grant Actions and Appropriations, 1966-1972 (Box 52)
  - Humanistic Scholarship and Research -- Divisional Reserve/Grant Actions and Appropriations, 1968-1970 (Box 52)
  - Independent Schools -- Background, 1962-1973 (Box 52)
  - Independent Schools -- Consultants, 1962-1974 (Box 52)
  - Independent Schools -- Evaluation, 1969-1974 (Box 52)
  - Independent Schools -- Forms, 1963-1972 (Box 52)
  - Independent Schools -- Grant Actions and Appropriations, 1962-1967 (Box 52)
  - Playwrights Program -- Background, 1961-1975 (Box 52)
  - Playwrights Program -- Consultants, 1965-1966 (Box 52)
  - Playwrights Program -- Grant Actions, 1964-1974 (Box 52)
  - Playwrights Program -- Judges Corresponence, 1965-1970 (Box 52)
  - Playwrights Program -- Summaries, 1966-1975 (Box 52)
  - Professional Training Appropriation -- Background, 1963-1966 (Box 52)
  - Professional Training Appropriation -- Grant Actions and Appropriations, 1963-1971 (Box 52)
  - Professional Training Appropriation -- Consultants, 1965 (Box 52)
  - Recording/Publication Project -- Background (1/3), 1961-1975 (Box 52)
  - Recording/Publication Project -- Background (2/3), 1961-1975 (Box 52)
  - Recording/Publication Project -- Background (3/3), 1961-1975 (Box 52)
  - Recording/Publication Project -- Forms, 1960-1977 (Box 52)
  - Recording/Publication Project -- Background II -- Drafts, 1969-1976 (Box 52)
  - Recording/Publication Project -- Grant Actions, 1969-1975 (Box 52)
  - Recording/Publication Project -- Policy Interpretations, 1970-1975 (Box 52)
  - Recording/Publication Project -- Press Releases, 1970-1975 (Box 52)
  - Recording/Publication Project -- Statistics, 1974-1977 (Box 52)
  - Conferences -- General, 1961-1967 (Box 53)
  - Conferences -- Communications in the Theater, Dec 18-19, 1959 (Box 53)
  - Conferences -- Visual Arts, Jun 8-9, 1961 (Box 53)
  - Conferences -- Theater Director, Aug 21, 1961 (Box 53)
  - Conferences -- Poets and Fiction Writers, Aug 22, 1961 (Box 53)
  - Conferences -- Playwrights, Aug 23, 1961 (Box 53)
  - Conferences -- Concert Artists, Aug 24, 1961 (Box 53)
  - Conferences -- Concert Artists, Aug 25, 1961 (Box 53)
  - Conferences -- Retrospective Exhibitions, Aug 26, 1961 (Box 53)
  - Conferences -- Regional Ballet Students, Aug 28, 1961 (Box 53)
  - Conferences -- Financial Problems of Young Artists, Apr 16, 1962 (Box 53)
  - Conferences -- Architects and Designers, Jun 14-15, 1962 (Box 53)
  - Conferences -- Opera, Feb 13, 1963 (Box 53)
  - Conferences -- Ballet, Aug 9, 1963 (Box 53)
  - Conferences -- Archaeology, May 4, 1964 (Box 53)
  - Conferences -- Translations, Aug 16, 1964 (Box 53)
  - Conferences -- Curatorial Training, Oct 22, 1964 (Box 53)
  - Conferences -- Museum Curatorial Training Program conference recording, 1966 April 4 (Box 72, Reel AV 6301)
    Place: Ford Foundation offices. Present: Merrill Rueppel, Dallas Museum of Fine Arts, Andrew Ritchie, Yale University Art Gallery, Laurence Sickman, Nelson Gallery, and Marcia Thompson.
  - Conferences -- Museum Curatorial Training Program conference recording, 1966 April 5 (Box 72, Reel AV 6302)
  - Conferences -- Program for Catalogues of American Fine Arts Collections meeting recording, 1966 April 5 (Box 72, Reel AV 6307)
    Place: Ford Foundation offices. Present: Andrew Ritchie, Yale University Art Gallery, Laurence Sickman, Nelson Gallery, and Marcia Thompson.
  - Conferences -- Archaeology, Oct 23, 1964 (Box 53)
  - Conferences -- Symphony Orchestras, Jul 13, 1965 (Box 53)
  - Conferences -- Archaeology, May 20-21, 1966 (Box 53)
    - Conferences -- Archaeology conference recording, 1966 May 20 (Box 72, Reel AV 6308)
      Place: Ford Foundation offices. Present: Robert M. Adams, John Caskey, Ernst Kitzinger, Albert C. Spaulding, Raymond H. Thompson, Sigmund Koch, Edward F. D'Arms, and Marcia Thompson.
    - Conferences -- Archaeology conference recording, 1966 May 20-21 (Box 72, Reel AV 6309)
  - Conferences -- Actor's Training, Dec 20, 1966 (Box 53)
  - Conferences -- Situation of the Artist and Institutions in the Arts, Nov 3-4, 1967 (Box 53)
  - Conferences -- TV and the Arts, Nov 17-18, 1967 (Box 53)
  - Conferences -- Production Subsidies of Performing Arts Groups, May 15-16, 1969 (Box 53)
  - Conferences -- Post-doctoral Fellowships for Young Humanists, Jan 7, 1970 (Box 53)
  - Conferences -- Planning Session for Proposed Title III Directors Meeting, Jan 23, 1970 (Box 53)
  - Conferences -- Representatives of Title III Arts Projects, May 5-7, 1970 (Box 53)
  - Conferences -- Performing Arts Organizations, Oct 19, 1970-Feb 17, 1971 (Box 53)
  - Conferences -- Economic and Financial Survey of Performing Groups, Nov 29-Dec 1, 1971 (Box 53)
  - Conferences -- Arts Documentation, Mar 16, 1973 (Box 53)
  - Conferences -- Art Museum Directors and Trustees, Apr 6-7, 1973 (Box 53)
  - Conferences -- Ballet Evaluation, Apr 27, 1972 (Box 53)
  - Conferences -- Television Arts Project, Sep 5, 1973 (Box 53)
  - Conferences -- Humanities and the Arts Division, Nov 26, 1973 (Box 53)
  - Conferences -- Reshaping Program Planning for Humanities and the Arts Division, Nov 25-Dec 6, 1974 (Box 53)
  - Film Makers Program -- Background, 1963-1969 (Box 53)
    See also Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) 06490199 (PA64-199), PROGRAM FOR FILM MAKERS.
  - Film Makers Program -- Correspondence, 1963-1965 (Box 53)
  - Film Makers Program -- Evaluation, 1973 (Box 53)
  - Film Makers Program -- Forms, 1963 (Box 53)
  - Film Makers Program -- Grant Actions, 1971 (Box 53)
  - Film Makers Program -- Grantees, 1964-1970 (Box 53)
    Grantees include: Kenneth Anger, Jordan Belson, James Blue, Bruce Conner, Carmen D'Avino, Daniel Drasin, Edmund Emshwiller, Hilary T. Harris, Helen Levitt, Kent Mackenzie, John R. McDermott, and Stanley Vanderbeek.
  - Film Makers Program -- Han Brothers, 1964 (Box 53)
  - Film Makers Program -- Judges' Correspondence, 1964 (Box 53)
  - Film Makers Program -- Judges Meeting, 1964 (Box 53)
  - Film Makers Program -- Nominators, 1964 (Box 53)
  - Film Makers Program -- Nominees, 1963 (Box 53)
  - Film Makers Program -- Nominations, 1963 (Box 53)
  - Film Makers Program -- Storage, 1974 (Box 53)
  - Special (Review) Committee -- Miscellaneous, 1962 (Box 53)
  - Special (Review) Committee -- Humanities and the Arts Reports, 1962 (Box 53)
  - Special (Review) Committee -- Scholarship and Basic Research, 1962 (Box 53)
  - Medical School Advisory Committee -- Correspondence -- Form Letters to Committee Members, 1956-1957 (Box 54)
  - Medical School Advisory Committee -- Correspondence -- Dubridge-Jacobson Correspondence, 1957 (Box 54)
  - Medical School Advisory Committee -- Correspondence -- Berry, George P, 1957 (Box 54)
  - Medical School Advisory Committee -- Correspondence -- Bronk, Detlev W., 1957 (Box 54)
  - Medical School Advisory Committee -- Correspondence -- Carmichael, Leonard, 1957 (Box 54)
  - Medical School Advisory Committee -- Correspondence -- Darley, Ward, 1957 (Box 54)
  - Medical School Advisory Committee -- Correspondence -- Dingle, John H., 1957 (Box 54)
  - Medical School Advisory Committee -- Correspondence -- Dubridge, Lee A., 1957 (Box 54)
  - Medical School Advisory Committee -- Correspondence -- Falk, Leon, 1957 (Box 54)
  - Medical School Advisory Committee -- Correspondence -- Greene, A. Crawford., 1957 (Box 54)
  - Medical School Advisory Committee -- Correspondence -- Hanes, Robert M., 1957 (Box 54)
  - Medical School Advisory Committee -- Correspondence -- Jacobson, Carlyle, 1957 (Box 54)
  - Medical School Advisory Committee -- Correspondence -- Lasker, Mrs. Albert D., 1957 (Box 54)
  - Medical School Advisory Committee -- Correspondence -- Loeb, Robert F., 1957 (Box 54)
  - Medical School Advisory Committee -- Correspondence -- Loomis, W.F., 1957 (Box 54)
  - Medical School Advisory Committee -- Correspondence -- Murphy, Franklin M., 1957 (Box 54)
  - Medical School Advisory Committee -- Correspondence -- Woodruf, Robert W., 1957 (Box 54)
  - Medical School Advisory Committee -- Meetings and Reports -- Reports to Foundation, 1956-1957 (Box 54)
  - Medical School Advisory Committee -- Meetings and Reports -- Meeting, Jul 11, 1956 (Box 54)
  - Medical School Advisory Committee -- Meetings and Reports -- Meeting, Nov 26, 1956 (Box 54)
  - Medical School Advisory Committee -- Eligible Institutions -- Form Letters to Medical Schools, 1956-1957 (Box 54)
  - Medical School Advisory Committee -- Ineligible Institutions -- Correspondence, 1956 (Box 54)
  - Medical School Advisory Committee -- Policy and Planning -- Chronological History of Medical School Grants Program -- Committee Materials and Actions, 1956-1957 (Box 54)
  - Medical School Advisory Committee -- Policy and Planning -- Chronological History of Medical School Grants Program -- Foundation Actions, 1956 (Box 54)
  - Medical School Advisory Committee -- Policy and Planning -- First Payment Letter, 1956 (Box 54)
  - Medical School Advisory Committee -- Policy and Planning -- Second Payment Letter, 1957 (Box 54)
  - Medical School Advisory Committee -- Policy and Planning -- Staff Memoranda and Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1956 (Box 54)
  - Medical School Advisory Committee -- Policy and Planning -- Correspondence with Ford Foundation Trustees re: Committee Formation and Actions and Recommendations, 1956 (Box 54)
  - Medical School Advisory Committee -- Policy and Planning -- Correspondence re: Formation of Committee, 1956 (Box 54)
  - Medical School Advisory Committee -- Policy and Planning -- Meeting of ME School Representatives in New York, Sep 28, 1956 (Box 54)
  - Medical School Advisory Committee -- Policy and Planning -- Meeting of ME School Representatives in Chicago, Oct 4, 1956 (Box 54)
  - Medical School Advisory Committee -- Policy and Planning -- Questionnaires, 1956 (Box 54)
  - Medical School Advisory Committee -- Policy and Planning -- Staff Memoranda re: Public Medical Schools, 1956 (Box 54)
  - Medical School Advisory Committee -- Statistical Data, 1956 (Box 54)
  - Medical School Advisory Committee -- Report to the Rockefeller Foundation, Nov 1, 1955 (Box 54)
  - Museum Curatorial Training Program -- Correspondence/Training Site Requests, 1962-1973 (Box 55)
  - Museum Curatorial Training Program -- Form Letters to Nominators and Application Stats, 1964-1972 (Box 55)